

+91-9030401416

🗹 nikhildulam@gmail.com

Hyderabad, Telangana

www.nikhildulam.me

SUMMARY

Precise Finance and Accounts Specialist with 4 years of experience Specialization in accounting, auditing, budgeting and taxation for diverse organizations. Advanced knowledge of preparing financial statements and understanding financial reports. Thorough understanding of income tax, GST and various applicable laws.

SKILLS

Account reconciliation specialist Book keeping Accounting principles Income Tax And GST law understanding

Well-versed with accounting software Tally Advanced MS-Excel and Data Analysis Financial Management

Financial records review MIS Bank Reconciliation Auditing

WORK EXPERIENCE

Accounts Assistant National Seeds Corporation Jul 2018 – Present Limited, Hyderabad

- Processed payments and documents such as invoices, journal vouchers, employee reimbursements and statements.
- Preparation and review of Bank Reconciliation Statements, Input Tax Credit Reconciliation under GST, and Other management reports like MIS reports.
- Used accounting software to prepare weekly and monthly financial reports.
- Preparation of financial statements such as Balance Sheet, Profit and Loss A/c and Cash Flow Statements as per Schedule-III of Companies Act, 2013.
- Reported financial data and updated financial records in ledgers and journals.
- Filing of GST and TDS Returns

Visiting Faculty VISIONN CS INSTITUTE, Aug 2017 - Mar 2020 Hyderabad

EDUCATION

CMA- Inter: Finance	INSTITUTE OF C	OST ACCOUNTANTS	OF 55.25%	Jan 2021 - Jan :	2022
Master Of Commerce: Finance	Osmania Unive	rsity	72%	Jul 2015 - Jun	2017
Bachelor of Commerce: Accounts and Finance	Osmania Unive	rsity	74%	Jul 2012 - Apr	2015
Intermediate: Field of Study	Board of intern	nediate Education	89%	Jun 2009 - May	2011
SSC: Field of Study	Board of secon	dary Education	88%	Apr 2008 - Apr 2	2009

SOFTWARES

Tally ERP and Tally Prime | SAP-FICO | MS -Excel

CERTIFICATIONS

Advanced Excel for Data Analysis

Mar 2017 - Present

Tally

Jan 2015 - Present

PROJECTS

Research Papers

- Impact of GST on Indian Economy, National Seminar on GST: Issues and Implications conducted by Department of commerce NIZAM College
- Payments Banks in India, International seminar on "Commerce Education -New Paradigms in Accounting and Finance" organised by Department of commerce Osmania University, Hyderabad

Research Publications & Projects

- FDI in India's Insurance Sector, Global Insurance Practices and Outlook, GLOBAL RESEARCH SOCIETY PUBLICATIONS
 ISBN 978-93-85817-00-7
- Demonetization effect on Indian stock market, Commerce Department, Osmania University, Jan 2017 -Apr 2017

LANGUAGES

English | Hindi | Telugu

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Resourceful Accounts Assistant knowledgeable in Tally ERP, SAP-FICO and MS Excel. Meticulous multi-tasker bringing 4 years of experience handling bookkeeping activities and correcting accounting errors. Skilled at analyzing complex situations and finding unorthodox solutions to challenging problems.